HAMADA S. BADR

Senior Applied Scientist

Customer Service Forecasting Science

Amazon

410-404-6354 badr@jhu.edu hsbadr.github.io

linkedin.com/in/hsbadr

SUMMARY

Today, there are many skilled and talented scientists applying their abilities to solve challenging problems in their field and contributing to the scientific literature. It is rare, however, to find interdisciplinary scientists who dynamically combine multiple disciplines, creative ideas, and innovative approaches to solve complex real-world problems using machine learning and numerical simulations. I am an applied scientist with broad and in-depth skills and over two decades of experience in statistical analysis, numerical modeling of physical processes, data visualization, and software engineering as well as project management and leadership. I am a language-agnostic software developer who can easily and quickly switch between different platforms and master new solutions. I am trained first in aerospace engineering and earth sciences, and I have developed my skills in software engineering, mathematics, statistics, machine learning, and physics to address grand challenges in aerodynamics, hydroclimate, infectious diseases, global health, and business intelligence.

EDUCATION

2011 - 2016

Baltimore, Maryland, United States

2011 - 2013

Baltimore, Maryland, United States

2003 - 2011

Giza, Egypt

1997 - 2003

Giza, Egypt

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Earth Sciences

The Johns Hopkins University (JHU)

Master of Arts - MA, Earth Sciences

The Johns Hopkins University (JHU)

Master of Science - MS, Aerospace Engineering Cairo University (CU)

Bachelor of Science - BS, Aerospace Engineering
Cairo University (CU)

EXPERIENCE

09/2022 - Present

Seattle, Washington, United States

Senior Applied Scientist

Amazon, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Customer Service Forecasting Science

· Develop automated and scalable scientific framework for contact demand forecasting.

AWS Sales, Marketing & Global Services Operations

· Uncover stages, inflection points, dwell times, insights, and drivers of end-to-end customer journeys.

08/2011 - 09/2022

Baltimore, Maryland, United States

Associate Research Scientist

The Johns Hopkins University (JHU)

Department of Civil and Systems Engineering (CaSE)

 Develop an environmentally informed risk monitoring and early warning system for potential reemergence of COVID-19.

Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences (EPS)

 Incorporate machine learning (ML), artificial intelligence (AI), and high-performance computing (HPC) in interdisciplinary scientific research.

09/2005 - 08/2018

Cairo, Egypt

Group Chief Executive | Assistant Research Scientist

National Authority for Remote Sensing & Space Sciences (NARSS)

Data Reception, Analysis & Receiving Station Affairs

 Improve numerical weather modeling and prediction using remote sensing, statistical modeling, data assimilation, and ensemble forecasting.